Guide to the E. S. Reddy Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
E. S. Reddy papers
1913-2010
1963-2001
MS 1499
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
56.27
(83 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence and printed material relating to South Africa and Namibia and document E. S. Reddy's work with anti-apartheid organizations around the world. Also included is material on Mahatma Gandhi and Indians in South Africa.
Reddy, E. S., 1924-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of E. S. Reddy, 1998-2001, 2003, 2005, 2006, and 2008. Transferred from the African Collection curator, 2013-2014.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
Materials in the original accession are arranged topically. Additional accessions are arranged as received from the African Collection curator.
Biographical / Historical
Enuga Sreenivasulu Reddy was born on July 1, 1924, in Pallaprolu, India. He received his B.A. from the University of Madras in 1943 and a M.A. from New York University in 1948. Reddy joined the United Nations Secretariat as a political affairs officer in 1949. From 1963 to 1965, Reddy was the principal secretary for the United Nations Special Committee Against Apartheid. He served as chief of the Section for African Questions from 1965 to 1976. In 1976 Reddy was appointed the director of the United Nations Centre Against Apartheid, a position he held until 1983. During this time he also served as director of the U.N. Trust Fund for South Africa and the U. N. Educational and Training Program for Southern Africa. Reddy was the assistant secretary-general of the United Nations from 1983 until his retirement in 1985.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence and printed material relating to South Africa and Namibia and document E. S. Reddy's work with anti-apartheid organizations around the world. Also included is material on Mahatma Gandhi and Indians in South Africa.
Anti-apartheid movements; Apartheid -- Namibia; Apartheid -- South Africa; Gandhi, Mahatma, 1869-1948; Reddy, E. S., 1924-; Tambo, Oliver, 1917-1993; United Nations Centre Against Apartheid
- Subject files
  - Abantwang Bazabalaza: Children Resist, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ACP -EEC, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Action Against Apartheid, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Affidavits and Memoranda on Behalf of Accused, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Africa Bureau, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Africa Information Centre, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Africa Institute of South Africa, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Africa Institute of the Academy of Sciences of the USSR, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - African American Institute: Saspost, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - African American Labor Center, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - African American Review, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - African Arts Fund Inc., 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - African Bibliographic Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "African Clarion", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - African Studies Society of India, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Afriquel Australe Actualites: Southern Africa Focus, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Afro-American Opinion, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Afro-Asian Council, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Aggett, Neil, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Airlines Serving South Africa, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Alegbe, Obadiah Oghoerore, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - American-African Affairs Association, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - American Banks, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - American Labor Education Center, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - American Medical Association, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - American Psychiatric Association, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - American Society of African Culture (AMSAC), 1963 (Box 1, Folder 30 - 31)
  - American Society of International Law, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Americans for Democratic Action, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Anglo-American Corporation, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Angola, 1971-1986 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Angola Information (London), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Anti-Apartheid Act, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Anti-Apartheid Groups, 1974-1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Apartheid and Business, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 39 - 40)
  - Apartheid Facts, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - ARENA, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Asian-African Legal Consultative Committee (New Delhi), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Association of the Bar of the City of New York, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Bank Loans to South Africa, 1973-1982 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Banned Persons, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Basutoland Congress Party, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Benson, Mary, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Berkeley, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Bhana, M. S., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Biko, Steve, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Bingham, Jonathan, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Black Media Workers Association (London), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Black Military Resistance League (Virginia), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Boesak, Allen, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Boraine, Alex, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Botswana, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Boycotts that Worked, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Brazil, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Breytenbach, Breyten, 1975-1986 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Société Africaine De Culture (Dakar), undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Britain, 1963-1990 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - British Actors Equity Association (London), 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - British Information Services, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - British Sports Council: Mission to South Africa, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - British Youth Council, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Brutus, Dennis, 1967-1983 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Bunting, Sidney, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Cabral, Amilcar, 1962-1973 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Canada, 1974-1984 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Canadian Labour Congress, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Canadian Sickle Cell Society, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Caribbean Contact, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Catholic Institute for International Relations (CIIR, London), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Centre for Applied Social Sciences: University of Natal, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Center for International Policy, 1973-1984 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Center for National Security Studies, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Cherry, Janet, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Chetty, Shun, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Chiba, Isoo, 1967-1981 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Chidzero, Bernard, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Chikane, Frank, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Children and Apartheid, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Chile, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Christian Instutite of Southern Africa, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Citizens Association for Racial Equality (CARE, New Zealand), 1976-1984 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - City of Atlanta, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Clergy and Laity Concerned, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Coetsee, Kobie, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Collaboration with South Africa, 1974-1978 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Collins, John L., 1975-1983 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Coloured Education, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Combined Economic Reporting Program (CERP), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Commission of the Churches on International Affairs, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Commission on Human Rights, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Committee Against Nigeria's Exploitation (CANE), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Committee of Concerned Citizens on Mercenary Activities, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Committee on Action Against Apartheid, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Commonwealth, 1983-1990 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Communist Party of Trinidad and Tobago, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Community, Resource and Information Centre (CRIC), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Congres Pan Africaniste (Algiers), 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Constitutional Rights Foundation, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - "Contact", 1963 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Cooper, Saths, 1971-1986 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Cornell University, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Council on African Affairs, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Council on Economic Priorities, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - "Cross Currents', 1992 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Crowther, C. Edward, 1967-1972 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Cultural Boycott of South Africa, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Curtis, Neville, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Dadoo, Yusuf, 1964-1979 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Dag Hammarskjold Information Centre on the Study of Violence and Peace (London), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Dalindyebo, Sabata, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Danish Association for International Cooperation, 1974-1985 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Davis Cup, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Davis, Irving, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Declaration of Berne (Switzerland), undated (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Decolonization, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Denationalization, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Development and Peace (Toronto), 1978 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Development Bank of Southern Africa, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Developments in South Africa, 1955-1965 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Diggs, Charles, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Dinkins, David, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Divison of Corporate and Social Mission (Atlanta), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Dokumentarische Information, undated (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Dukakis, Michael, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Duncan, Patrick, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Dutch Churches, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Eaton, Cyrus, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Ebrahim, Ismael E., 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Economic Expansion of South Africa, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Edmondson, Locksley, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Environmental Policy Center, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Essack. A. K., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Euromart Research Consultants, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - European Commission on Southern Africa, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - European Communities (EEC), 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Fact Finding Mission to the Front Line States of Southern Africa, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Federal Republic of Germany (FDR), 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Fine, Alan, undated (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Finland, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - First, Ruth, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Foreign Affairs Association, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Foreign Policy (of South Africa), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - Forman, Lionel, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Foundation for the Community of Artists, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - France, 1970-1984 (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Friedman, Julian, 1967-1976 (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - Friedmann, Marion, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - Fund for the Borough of Brooklyn, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - GDR Committee for Human Rights, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 155)
  - General Correspondence, 1964-1976 (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - German Democratic Republic, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - Ghana, 1958-1977 (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Ginwala, Frene, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Godinho, Jose Magalhaes, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - Gordimer, Nadine, 1969-1984 (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - Govender, Ronnie, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - Guide to International African Conferences, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - Gwala, Harry, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - Hackney Black People's Association (London), 1985 (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Harare Declaration, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - Harris, John, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - Hart, Gillian, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - Heritage Foundation, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - Holland, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - Hommel, Maurice, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 171)
  - Houser, George, 1981-1991 (Box 3, Folder 172)
  - Howard University, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 173)
  - Huddleston, Trevor, 1983-1988 (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - Hungary, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 175)
  - Hunger Strikes, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 176)
  - Imperial College of Science and Technology, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 177)
  - Indemnity Committee, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 178)
  - Information Centre of the World Peace Council (Finland), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 179)
  - India, 1936-1990 (Box 3, Folder 180-183)
    Scope and Contents
    File contains no materials for the period 1942-1980.
  - Institute for Independent Social Journalism, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 184)
  - Institute for Policy Studies, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 185)
  - Institute for Social Research (London), 1973 (Box 3, Folder 186)
  - Institute for Sport and Social Analysis, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 187)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 188)
  - Insitut für Internationale Begegnungen e. V. (Bonn), 1981-1988 (Box 3, Folder 189)
  - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility (ICCR), 1975-1991 (Box 3, Folder 190)
  - Inter-Governmental Maritime Consultative Organization (IMCO), 1974 (Box 3, Folder 191)
  - International Anti-Apartheid Year, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 192)
  - International Chamber of Commerce (ICC), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 193)
  - International Commission of Inquiry, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 194)
  - International Commission of Jurists (ICJ, Geneva), 1973-1992 (Box 3, Folder 195)
  - International Committee of the Red Cross, 1977-1986 (Box 3, Folder 196)
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU, Brussels), 1976-1986 (Box 3, Folder 197)
  - International Council of African Women, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 198)
  - International Days Relating to the Struggle in South Africa and Nimbia, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 199)
  - International Federation of Actors (FIA), 1981 (Box 3, Folder 200)
  - International Federation Terre des Hommes, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 201)
  - International Fundraising Consortium (London), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 202)
  - International Hearing on Political Violence in South Africa and the Implementation of the National Peace Accord, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 203)
  - International Labour Office (ILO, Geneva), 1973-1987 (Box 3, Folder 204)
  - International Law and Apartheid, undated (Box 3, Folder 205)
  - International Organization of Journalists, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 206)
  - International Programme for the Development of Communication (IPDC), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 207)
  - International Public Policy Institute (IPPI), 1983 (Box 3, Folder 208)
  - International Student and Youth Movement, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 209)
  - International Union of Students (Czechoslovakia), 1976-1983 (Box 3, Folder 210)
  - International University Exchange Fund (IUFF), 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 211)
  - International Youth and Student Movement for the United Nations (ISMUN), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 212)
  - Investment Boycotts, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 213)
  - Isaacs, Henry, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 214)
  - Israel, 1973-1981 (Box 4, Folder 215)
  - Italy, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 216)
  - Ivory Coast, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 217)
  - Jabbour, George, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 218)
  - Jacquesson, Alphonse J., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 219)
  - Jamaica, 1978-1987 (Box 4, Folder 220)
  - Jamaica Council for Human Rights (JCHR, Jamaica), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 221)
  - Johnson Foundation, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 222)
  - Joseph, Helen, 1966-1989 (Box 4, Folder 223)
  - Journalists, 1969-1985 (Box 4, Folder 224)
  - Kathrada, A. M., 1964-1989 (Box 4, Folder 225)
  - Kennedy, Robert, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 226)
  - King, Martin Luther on Apartheid, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 227)
  - Kleinschmidt, Horst, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 228)
  - Lagos, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 229)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 230)
  - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 231)
  - League of Women Voters of the City of New York, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 232)
  - Legum, Colin and Margaret, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 233)
  - Leichter, Franz S., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 234)
  - Lekota, Patrick Terror, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 235)
  - Lesotho, 1972-1983 (Box 4, Folder 236)
  - Liberation Support Movement, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 237)
  - Liberazione E. Sviluppo (Rome), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 238)
  - Lutheran Council in the USA, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 239)
  - Lutheran World Federation, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 240)
  - McNamara, Robert, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 241)
  - Makatini, M. Johnstone, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 242)
  - Makerere Institute of Social Research Library, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 243)
  - Mandela, Nelson, 1982-1990 (Box 4, Folder 244)
  - Mandela, Winnie, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 245)
  - Martin Luther King, Jr., Center for Social Change, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 246)
  - Massachusetts, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 247)
  - Mbeki, Thabo, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 248)
  - Medicine and Apartheid, 1968-1984 (Box 4, Folder 249)
  - Meer, I. C., 1982 (Box 4, Folder 250)
  - Michigan, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - Military Arms Embargo, 1963-1986 (Box 5, Folder 252-256)
  - Military Assistance to South Africa, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 257)
  - Minerals in South Africa, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 258)
  - Malteno, Robert, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 259)
  - Morobe, Murphy, 1984-1987 (Box 5, Folder 260)
  - Morris, Michael, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - Mothopeng Trial, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 262)
  - Mothopeng, Zeph, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 263)
  - Movement for Justice in Africa (MOJA), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 264)
  - Mozambique, Angola and Guinea Information Centre, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 265)
  - Mozambique Information Office, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 266)
  - Mozambique Support Network (Illinois), 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 267)
  - Mpetha, Oscar, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 268)
  - Naidoo, Goonam, 1983-1990 (Box 5, Folder 269)
  - Nair, Billy, 1978-1984 (Box 5, Folder 270)
  - Namibia, undated (Box 5, Folder 271)
  - National Alliance of Third World Journalists, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 272)
  - National and Local Government Officers Association (NALGO), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 273)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 274)
  - National Black United Front (NBUF), 1981-1985 (Box 5, Folder 275)
  - National Conference of Black Lawyers, 1980, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 276)
  - National Coordinating Committee for the Repatriation of South African Exiles (NCCR), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 277)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ, 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 278)
  - National Lawyers Guild, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 279)
  - National Student Coalition Against Racism, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 280)
  - National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees (New York), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 281)
  - National Union of Students (United Kingdom), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 282)
  - Naude, Beyers, 1977-1985 (Box 5, Folder 283)
  - Ndondo, Batandwa, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 284)
  - Nehru Memorial Museum, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 285)
  - New Testament Church, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 286)
  - New York, 1976-1987 (Box 5, Folder 287)
  - New York City Employees' Retirement System, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 288)
  - New Zealand, 1976-1984 (Box 5, Folder 289)
  - New Zealand Medical Association (Wellington), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 290)
  - News from the Film Fund, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 291)
  - Newsclippings
    - 1977-1992 (Box 5, Folder 292-298)
    - 1993 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - Nigeria, 1960-1984 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - Nkomati Accord, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 300)
  - Nokwe, Philemon Dumo, 1963-1978 (Box 6, Folder 301)
  - Non-Governmental Organization (NGO), 1971-1993 (Box 6, Folder 302)
  - Northwestern University, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 303)
  - Norway, 1983-1986 (Box 6, Folder 304)
  - Nyembe, Dorothy, 1977-1984 (Box 6, Folder 305)
  - Nzo, Alfred, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 306)
  - Occidental College, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 307)
  - Obituaries of South African Political Activists, 1968-1990 (Box 6, Folder 308)
  - Oil Companies, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 309)
  - Oil Embargo, 1970-1989 (Box 6, Folder 310-313)
  - Ordia, Abraham, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 314)
  - Organization of African Trade Union Unity (Ghana), 1978-1983 (Box 6, Folder 315)
  - Palme, Olof, speeches, 1966-1985 (Box 6, Folder 316 - 317)
  - Pan Africanist Congress (PAC), 1963-1989 (Box 6, Folder 318)
  - Panamercian/Panafrican Association (New York), 1989-1992 (Box 6, Folder 319)
  - Parliamentarians Global Action for Disarmament Development and World Reform, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 320)
  - Paton, Alan, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 321)
  - Peace for Our Children's Sake, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 322)
  - PEN America Center, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 323)
  - Pillay, Vella, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 324)
  - Policy Documents, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 325)
  - Political Activists, 1968-1986 (Box 6, Folder 326)
  - Political Trials in South Africa, 1978-1982 (Box 6, Folder 327)
  - Prager, Fred, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 328)
  - Program for Social Change, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 329)
  - Qoboza, Percy, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 330)
  - Ramgobin, Mewa, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 331)
  - Ramphele, Mamphela, 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 332)
  - "Reality", 1969 (Box 6, Folder 333)
  - Reddy, Govin, 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 334)
  - Reeves, Richard Ambrose, 1974-1980 (Box 6, Folder 335)
  - Repression of the Legal Profession in South Africa, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 336)
  - Resha, Robert, 1973-1985 (Box 6, Folder 337)
  - Resistance of Black Women, 1979-1983 (Box 7, Folder 338)
  - Revolutionary Communist Group (London), 1986 (Box 7, Folder 339)
  - Rhodesia, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 340)
  - Riverside Church, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 341)
  - "Rivonia" Trial, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 342)
  - Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Human Rights Award, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 343)
  - Rogers, B. J., 1971 (Box 7, Folder 344)
  - Rohan, Rafiq, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 345)
  - Royal Commonwealth Society, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 346)
  - Sachs, Albert, 1969-1990 (Box 7, Folder 347)
  - Sanctions Against South Africa, 1964-1987 (Box 7, Folder 348)
  - Schomberg Center, undated (Box 7, Folder 349)
  - Scott, Michael, 1964-1983 (Box 7, Folder 350)
  - Selective Purchasing Resolution, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 351)
  - Seton Hall University, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 352)
  - Seventieth Anniversary of the ANC, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 353)
  - Shipping Research Bureau (Amsterdam), 1981-1992 (Box 7, Folder 354)
  - Sibeko, David, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 355)
  - Sisulu, Walter, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 356)
  - Sisulu, Zwelakhe, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 357)
  - Sita, Nana, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 358)
  - Sobukwe, Robert, 1972-1978 (Box 7, Folder 359)
  - Socialist International (London), 1984 (Box 7, Folder 360)
  - Université Libre de Bruxelles, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 361)
  - Solidarity Committee (New York), 1982 (Box 7, Folder 362)
  - Solidarity Committee of the German Democratic Republic, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 363)
  - Solomon Mahlangu Freedom College (SOMAFCO), 1985 (Box 7, Folder 364)
  - South Africa, 1918-1987 (Box 7, Folder 365)
  - South Africa Federation, 1962-1985 (Box 7, Folder 366)
  - South Africa NOW, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 367)
  - South African Institute of Race Relations (SAIRR), 1976 (Box 7, Folder 368)
  - "South Atlantic Alliance", 1982 (Box 7, Folder 369)
  - South African Development Coordination Conference (SADCC), 1989 (Box 7, Folder 370)
  - Soyinka, Wole, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 371)
  - Sparks, Allister, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 372)
  - Special Economic Assistance Programme, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 373)
  - Sports Boycott, 1973-1988 (Box 7, Folder 374 - 376)
  - Sports Council (London), 1977 (Box 7, Folder 377)
  - Standing Committee of NGO's (SANAM Association), 1990 (Box 7, Folder 378)
  - Stanford African Students Association, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 379)